/* Created and coded by Abhilash Narayan */
/* Quiz source: w3schools.com */
var quiz = {
    "JS": [
    {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Anarkali digitally signs a message and sends it to Salim. Verification of the signature by Salim requires",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Anarkali's public key",
    "b": "salim's public key",
    "c": "salim's private key",
    "d": "Anarkali's private key",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Anarkali's public key",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The minimum positive integer p such that (3p modulo 17) = 1 is",

    "options": [
    {
    "a": "5",
    "b": "8",
    "c": "12",
    "d":"16"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "16",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "A sender is employing public key Cryptography to send a secret message to a receiver. Which one of the following statement is true?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "Sender encrypts using receiver's public key",
    "b": "Sender encrypts using his own public key",
    "c": "Receiver decrypts using sender's public key ",
    "d":"Receiver decrypts using his own public key",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "Sender encrypts using receiver's public key",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Identify the correct sequence in which the following packets are transmitted on the network by a host when a browser requests a webpage from a remote server, assuming that the host has just been restarted.",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "HTTP GET request,DNS query,TCP SYN ",
    "b": "DNS query,HTTP GET request,TCP SYN",
    "c":"DNS query,TCP SYN,HTTP GET request",
    "d":"TCP SYN,DNS query,HTTP GET request",

    }
    ],
    "answer": "DNS query,TCP SYN,HTTP GET request",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The set {1,2,4,7,8,11,13,14} is a group under multiplication modulo 15. The inverse of 4 and 7 are respectively:Which one of the following protocols is NOT used to resolve one form of address to another one?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "DNS",
    "b": "ARP",
    "c": "DHCP",
    "d": "RARP",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "DHCP",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "In one of the pairs of protocols given below, both the protocols can use multiple TCP connections between the same client and the server. Which one is that?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "HTTP,FTP",
    "b": "HTTP,TELNET",
    "c": "FTP,SMTP",
    "d":"HTTP,SMTP",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "HTTP,SMTP",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which one of the following uses UDP as the transport protocol?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "HTTP",
    "b": "Telnet",
    "c": "DNS",
    "d":"SMTP",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "DNS",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Identify the correct order in which a server process must invoke the function calls accept, bind, listen, and recv according to UNIX socket APL",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "listen,accept,bind recv",
    "b": "bind,listen,accept,recv",
    "c": "bind,accept,listen,recv",
    "d": "accept,listen,bind,recv",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "bind,listen,accept,recv",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which one of the following is TRUE about the interior gateway routing protocols â€“ Routing Information Protocol (RIP) and Open Shortest Path First (OSPF)?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "RILP uses distance vector routing and OSPF uses link state routing",
    "b": "OSPF uses distance vector routing and RIP uses link state routing",
    "c": "Both RIP and OSPF use link state routing",
    "d": "Both RIP and OSPF use distance vector routing"
    }
    ],
    "answer": "RILP usues distence vector routing and OSPF uses link state routing",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    },
    {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Consider a CSMA/CD network that transmits data at a rate of 100 Mbps (108 bits second) over a 1 km(kilometer) cable with no repeaters. If the minimum frame size required for this network is 1250 bytes, what is the signal speed (km/sec) in the cable?",
    "options": [
    {
    "a": "8000",
    "b": "10000",
    "c": "16000",
    "d": "20000",
    }
    ],
    "answer": "20000 ",
    "score": 0,
    "status": ""
    }
   
    ]
    }
    var quizApp = function () {
    this.score = 0;
    this.qno = 1;
    this.currentque = 0;
    var totalque = quiz.JS.length;
    this.displayQuiz = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = cque;
    if (this.currentque < totalque) {
    $("#tque").html(totalque);
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#next").attr("disabled", false);
    $("#qid").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].id + '.');
    $("#question").html(quiz.JS[this.currentque].question);
    $("#question-options").html("");
    for (var key in quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0]) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0].hasOwnProperty(key)) {
    $("#question-options").append(
    "<div class='form-check option-block'>" +
    "<label class='form-check-label'>" +
    "<input type='radio' class='form-check-input' name='option' id='q" + key + "' value='" + quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] + "'><span id='optionval'>" +
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].options[0][key] +
    "</span></label>"
    );
    }
    }
    }
    if (this.currentque <= 0) {
    $("#previous").attr("disabled", true);
    }
    if (this.currentque >= totalque) {
    $('#next').attr('disabled', true);
    for (var i = 0; i < totalque; i++) {
    this.score = this.score + quiz.JS[i].score;
    }
    return this.showResult(this.score);
    }
    }
    this.showResult = function (scr) {
    $("#result").addClass('result');
    $("#result").html("<h1 class='res-header'>Total Score: &nbsp;" + scr + '/' + totalque + "</h1>");
    for (var j = 0; j < totalque; j++) {
    var res;
    if (quiz.JS[j].score == 0) {
    res = '<span class="wrong">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-remove c-wrong"></i>';
    } else {
    res = '<span class="correct">' + quiz.JS[j].score + '</span><i class="fa fa-check c-correct"></i>';
    }
    $("#result").append(
    '<div class="result-question"><span>Q ' + quiz.JS[j].id + '</span> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].question + '</div>' +
    '<div><b>Correct answer:</b> &nbsp;' + quiz.JS[j].answer + '</div>' +
    '<div class="last-row"><b>Score:</b> &nbsp;' + res +
    '</div>'
    );
    }
    }
    this.checkAnswer = function (option) {
    var answer = quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer;
    option = option.replace(/</g, "&lt;") //for <
    option = option.replace(/>/g, "&gt;") //for >
    option = option.replace(/"/g, "&quot;")
    if (option == quiz.JS[this.currentque].answer) {
    if (quiz.JS[this.currentque].score == "") {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].score = 1;
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "correct";
    }
    } else {
    quiz.JS[this.currentque].status = "wrong";
    }
    }
    this.changeQuestion = function (cque) {
    this.currentque = this.currentque + cque;
    this.displayQuiz(this.currentque);
    }
    }
    var jsq = new quizApp();
    var selectedopt;
    $(document).ready(function () {
    jsq.displayQuiz(0);
    $('#question-options').on('change', 'input[type=radio][name=option]', function (e) {
    //var radio = $(this).find('input:radio');
    $(this).prop("checked", true);
    selectedopt = $(this).val();
    });
    });
    $('#next').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(1);
    });
    $('#previous').click(function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
    if (selectedopt) {
    jsq.checkAnswer(selectedopt);
    }
    jsq.changeQuestion(-1);
    });